### Contact

www.linkedin.com/in/david-nico-lopez (LinkedIn)

## Top Skills

Python

Swift

**JavaScript** 

## Languages

English (Native or Bilingual)

Spanish (Native or Bilingual)

## Honors-Awards

McLean County Outstanding STEM Student

Illinois Wesleyan Entrepreneurial Fellowship Grant

Best Hardware Hack at HackHarvard

### **Publications**

**Quasi-fortunate Numbers** 

# **David Nico Lopez**

Facebook SWE Intern | ACM Chapter President | Caption\_it Founder Bloomington Heights

# Summary

A driven team leader and meme-connoisseur, David Nico Lopez is the CEO of Caption\_it, an award-winning mobile meme game that brings people together through humor. He has simultaneous interests in entrepreneurship and academic research with a primary focus on software development. This summer, Nico will be working as a software engineering intern at Facebook in Menlo Park.

# Experience

Facebook

Software Engineering Intern

June 2020 - Present (3 months)

Menlo Park

WhatsApp - iOS Core Infrastructure

#### **Pinterest**

Software Engineering Technical Scholar July 2019 - August 2019 (2 months)

San Francisco Bay Area

- Developed technical and professional skills through Pinterest mentorship to excel in Software Engineering positions

State Farm ®

Innovation Research Scholar

May 2019 - August 2019 (4 months)

Bloomington/Normal, Illinois Area

- Simulated DNA dynamics to better understand cancer formation and aging, and analyzed cancer data to model tumor formation.
- Submitted our results to the Journal of Computational Biology.

Illinois Wesleyan University

1 year 6 months

Research Assistant

October 2018 - May 2019 (8 months)

Bloomington/Normal, Illinois Area

Working on simulating several micromagnetic environments with the GPU-accelerated software MUMAX3.

#### **Teacher Assistant**

December 2017 - April 2019 (1 year 5 months)

Bloomington/Normal, Illinois Area

- Supplemented course lectures by teaching bi-weekly recitations on functional programming and discrete math.
- Tutored introductory Mechanics and Electromagnetism.

Gorilla Group Software Engineer Intern June 2018 - August 2018 (3 months) Greater Chicago Area

- Built interactions for mobile and web apps using JavaScript
- Developed templates with Vue.js to interface with Magento, an E-commerce Content Management System.

## Education

Illinois Wesleyan University

Bachelor of Science - BS, Computer Science · (2017 - 2021)